Shane Holloman Resume

DevOps Systems Engineer • Cybersecurity Student

PH: +64 22-355-4600 Wellington NZ

shaneholloman@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaneholloman

https://bit.ly/holloman-resume

Systems / DevOps Engineer. Currently studying Cybersecurity for the Cisco CyberOps Certification.

The last 5 years in New Zealand was as an IT manager that included system engineering, turnkey on-premise infrastructure builds, large-scale render farms, and client solutions with some DevOps for a video photogrammetry company. That startup had some 90+ folks employed at one point. This required quite a bit of on-premise IT infrastructure design and deployment in multiple countries both for us and our clients. I learned Ansible as a tool to commission bare metal render farms and maintain systems in Wellington, Seoul, and Tokyo. That job was pretty awesome most of the time. Probably the best part was the fact I was always learning something new and occasionally having my hat handed to me by some left field challenge. It was my first startup and I would definitely do another if I had the chance.

My past before said startup has been a 50/50 split of technical and creative experiences. I have a past background in on-set production and post VFX / Compositing which also includes on-set and post audio for small movies, music, and commercials in Nashville and New York City. Today, I'm currently studying CyberSecurity and [Shooting ocean sports](https://www.kite.nz) in my spare time.

PROFESSIONAL SKILL SET

On Prem and Cloud DevOps
Ansible Automation
Server Administration
Bare Metal deployment via Maas
Virtualization and Hypervisors

HOBBY SKILL SET

Unreal Engine
Photography
Digital Art
Photogrammetry
Blockchain use cases

CURRENT FOCUS

Cybersecurity, Ansible, Docker, VMs, Kubernetes, Remote Linux Windows multiboot Systems, Automation, Stack Development, Linux and Windows Server Management, Networking, Bash Scripting





RECENT EXPERIENCE

IT MANAGER • DEVOPS SYSTEMS ENGINEER - 81 LTD

January 2016 - January 2020

IT Manager • DevOps and System Engineer • Ansible Automation • MaaS Bare Metal Deployments

Tools Used Ansible, Docker, Linux (OpenSuse, CentOS, Ubuntu), MaaS, Virtualization, Windows Server/Active Directory, Networking, Scripting (Bash and PowerShell), Databases (MySQL, Elasticsearch, MongoDB), Statistic solutions (Prometheus and Grafana),

Shane Holloman Resume

DevOps Systems Engineer • Cybersecurity Student

PAST EXPERIENCE

IT MANAGER • DIGITAL ASSETS MANAGER - TRAFFIC

February 2012 - 2019 Weekend work

IT Manager • Digital Assets Manager • Wordpress Dev. Full stack deployments

Tools Used Ansible, Linux, Nginx, Bash Scripting, Git, Vscode, SSH, Illustrator, Lightroom, Photography, Excel Scripting

WEB DEVELOPER • DIGITAL ARTIST • MARKETING - UNITEDSAINTS

January 2007 - Present (8 years)

Server Stacks • SMS / SIP Logic • VFX • Digital Art

Tools Used Linux, Nginx, Bash Scripting, HTML, CSS, Frontend frameworks, WordPress, Github, SSH, Illustrator, Lightroom, Photography, Excel, Google Apps, Nuke, Maya, Cinema 4D, Daz3D, Capture One, PTGui

PAST EXPERIENCE

IT ADMINISTRATOR • WEB DEVELOPER - REALWATER INC

November 2011 - August 2012 (10 months)

IT Administrator, Digital Artist, Web Development, eCommerce, Quickbooks, Branding and Marketing Concepts, Product Visualization through final Production.

COMPOSITOR • STEREOGRAPHER - ZOE CREATIVE SERVICES, LLC

2010 - 2011 (1 year)

Lead Compositor, Technical Director, OS X Server Deployment and Administration.

MAC SPECIALIST - APPLE INC

2005 - 2007 (1.5 years)

I worked as a Mac Specialist with the creative department as a software trainer for a little over a year and really loved it. Whereas sales was a primary hired objective, I was typically training clients daily.

LIVE TELEVISION STAGE MANAGER - NASHVILLE STAR AT USA NETWORKS

2002 - 2006 (4 years)

Stage managing principal talent, namely the Host and their respective teams for live broadcast television.

STUDIES

Currently studying for Cisco CyberOps Certification, NZ - Cybersecurity 2021 - Present

EDUCATION

New Horizon Technical College, USA - Digital Art, 1996 - 1996 The University of Georgia, USA - BA, Music Performance, 1993 - 1994

Grand Canyon University, USA - BA, Commercial Music, 1990 - 1992

Middleton Grange, NZ - General Studies, Fine & Studio Arts, 1985 - 1987

Christchurch Boys High, NZ - General, Focus: Art and Music, 1983 - 1984

Heaton Street Intermediate, NZ - General, Focus: Art and Music, 1981 - 1982